

Romel Aoingan Osorio, RC, CSP, CSMS, CST, CMPP

An experienced Security Professional with more than sixteen (16) years in the Security Industry, held various Supervisory and Managerial positions, trustworthy, result oriented, keen / attentive to details, can easily adapt to changes, can work with less / minimum supervision, firm / strict implementer and a team player.

OBJECTIVE:

To secure an employment in a reputable company wherein I can utilize, enhance and share my acquired knowledge, skills, trainings as well as experiences for mutual growth and success.

EDUCATION:

Level	School / University	Inclusive Dates	Degree / Course
Tortion	University of Baguio	1993 - 1997	Bachelor of Science in Criminology (Graduated)
Tertiary	Divine Word College of Bangued	1992 - 1993	Bachelor of Science in Commerce (Undergraduate)
Secondary	Divine Word College of Bangued	1988 - 1992	
Primary	Divine Word College of Bangued	1982 - 1988	

❖ CADETSHIP

PHILIPPINE NATIONAL POLICE ACADEMY (PNPA)

Bachelor of Science in Public Safety (Undergraduate)

May 2000 - December 2002

Full Government Scholar with a POLICE CADET Rank

WORK EXPERIENCE/S:

Security Industry

Loss Prevention Coordinator / Officer	Euroasia Philippines Inc.	September 19, 2019 to May 24, 2022
 Account / Project: Ambatovy Joint Venture East Africa) 	e (Nickel and Cobalt Mining Co	ompany - Madagascar,

- Directly reporting to the Lead Security Controller
- Acting Lead Security Controller (May to November 2021)
- ❖ Act as Security / Access Controller
- Assigned as Security Controller at the Security Control Room
- ❖ To ensure that all materials / equipment coming-in and out of the premises are with active Online Gate Pass (OGP)
- To ensure that all incoming and outgoing personnel and vehicles are with active badges
- To conduct patrolling within the area of responsibility
- ❖ To report all violations of employees (direct / contracted)
- To report all incidents
- Act as Overt / Mobile patroller
- To perform such other duties as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Asset and Site Protection Officer	DoubleDragon	July 16, 2017 to
Asset and site Protection Officer	Properties Corporation	September 15, 2019

- As an organic / In-house Officer: January 02 to September 15, 2019
- Under The 1st Eagle Guard Security Services, Inc.: July 16, 2017 to December 31, 2018
- Area of Responsibility: National Capital Region and Luzon 11 CityMalls, D8 Mall, two (2) Hotels, one (1) Condominium and one (1) Corporate and Residential Tower
- Directly reports to the Head of Security
- Conducts the following:
 - Investigation
 - Security Survey
 - o In-house Training / Seminar to all Security and Housekeeping Personnel
 - Quarterly Performance Review / Audit of all Security Personnel and Security Service Providers equipment's
 - o Field visits, inspection, monitoring and supervision of all sites
- Assist the Head of Security in the following:
 - Formulation of Policies and standards
 - o Opening of a site
- Liaise with Law Enforcement Agencies / Local Government Units having jurisdiction of the area
- Act as the Over-all in-charge / Ground Commander during special events such as celebrity mall tours
- Administer written examinations and oral interviews to all applicants (Security Officers / Guards) under my Area Of Responsibility (AOR)
- ❖ Act as coordinator between the client and Security Service Providers
- Perform such other functions as maybe directed

Security Specia	list II /	Home Credit Consumer	March 06 to			
Loss Prevention and Inves	tigation Specialist	Finance Philippines, Inc.	July 15, 2017			
Area of Responsibility: Abra, Ilocos Sur, Ilocos Norte and La Union Provinces						

- Reports directly to the Loss Prevention and Investigation Head
- Conducts the following:
 - Investigation into cases of theft, misappropriation, fraud, syndicated estafa and other financial crimes, violations of code of conduct and other employee misconduct
 - Personnel security background checks
 - Covert and overt investigations
 - Periodic loss prevention inspections and audits
 - Field visits
- Review and investigate suspicious activity as derived from the variety of sources
- Perform other duties as maybe directed

Area Manager	Jarton Security Agency, Inc.	September 10, 2016 to February 15, 2017
--------------	---------------------------------	---

- Account / Project: Market Market Mall, Bonifacio Global City
- Reports directly to the Property Manager, likewise to the Asset Protection Manager and incoordination with the Asset Protection Coordinator (Third Party Service Contractor)
- Conducts the following:
 - o Investigation of all reported incidents and likewise to erring personnel
 - Security Survey, Audit and inspection
 - Daily formation of troops
- Monitoring and supervision of more than one hundred (100) personnel (Security Officers and guards) and likewise the area
- Implement company policies, rules and regulations
- Act as the Over-all in-charge / Ground Commander during events such as celebrity mall tours
- ❖ Act as coordinator between the client and Security Service Provider
- Administer written examinations and oral interviews to all applicants (Security Officers / Guards)

to be deployed at Market Market Mall

Perform such other functions as maybe directed by Superior Officers

	Protection and Security Coordinator	Coca-cola FEMSA Philippines	September 11, 2014 to August 31, 2016
•	Area of Responsibility: National Capital Re Distribution Centers	gion and Bicol Region - Man	ufacturing plant and

- Directly reports to the Protection and Security Executive for Luzon Region
- Conducts the following:
 - o Investigation of alleged theft / robbery and fraud incidents amounting to one hundred thousand pesos (Php. 100, 000.00) and below
 - o Field visits, inspection, monitoring and supervision of all sites
 - o In-house Training / Seminar to all Security Personnel
 - Review and signing of billings for Security
 - o Background checks to all incoming employees within AOR
- Assist the Protection and Security Executive for Luzon Region in the formulation of Policies and standards
- * Assist in the protection of VIPs during field visits within my Area of Responsibility
- Liaise with Law Enforcement Agencies / Local Government Units having jurisdiction of the area.
- ❖ Administer written examinations and oral interviews to all applicants (Security Officers / Guards) to be deployed within my AOR
- Perform such other functions as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Operation Manager	St. Thomas Security and February 12 to		
Operation Manager	General Services, Corp.	September 10, 2014	

- Reports directly to the VP for Operations / Finance
- Conducts the following:
 - Investigation
 - o Background checks to all applicants before deployment
 - Security survey and inspection to all sites (Clients) and security personnel assigned to sites
 - o In-house training / seminar to all security personnel
- Liaise with Law Enforcement Agencies
- Design and submit budget proposals on company sponsored activities, trainings, company equipment, etc.
- Perform such other duties as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Plant Security Inspector	Philip Morris Fortune Tobacco Corp.	July 16 to December 31, 2013				
Area of Responsibility: Vigan City and Marikina City Plants						

- Reports directly to the Plant Security Officer
- * Reports directly to the Flant Se
- Conducts the following:
 - Investigation
 - o Intelligence and Information gathering
 - Background checks to all incoming employees
 - Audit and inspection
- Assist the Security Team in securing VIPs during site visits
- Monitoring and supervision of all personnel and area
- ❖ Member of the Plant Management / Leadership Team
- Implement company policies, rules and regulations
- Liaise with Law Enforcement Agencies / Local Government Units
- Administer written examinations and oral interviews to all applicants (Security Officers / Guards)
- Perform such other functions as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Intelligence and Investigation Security Officer	Eagle Matrix Security Agency, Inc.	March 01 to July 15, 2013			
 Account / Project: Philip Morris Fortune Tobacco Corporation Area of Responsibility: North - Central Luzon - Sales Offices 					
 Reports directly to the Area Sales Security Officer Conducts the following: 					

- - Investigation
 - o Intelligence and Information gathering
 - Background checks to all incoming employees
 - Audit and inspection of all sites (Sales Offices)
- ❖ Assist the Security Team in securing VIPs during site visits
- Monitoring and supervision of all personnel and area
- Implement company policies, rules and regulations
- Liaise with Law Enforcement Agencies / Local Government Units
- Perform such other functions as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Security Director	Ace and Associates Risk Management, Inc.	May 02, 2012 to January 31, 2013

- Account / Project: Pascual Laboratories, Inc.
- Area of Responsibility: Quezon City (Head Office / Sub-office), Nueva Ecija (Farm) and Bulacan (Manufacturing Plant)
- ❖ Directly reports to the President of Pascual Laboratories, Inc. and likewise to the Senior Associate of Ace And Associates Risk Management Consultancy, Inc.
- Conducts the following:
 - Investigation
 - o Field visits, inspection, monitoring and supervision of all sites
 - Background checks to all incoming employees
- ❖ Design and submit budget proposals for all Team sponsored activities, field visits and department materials
- ❖ Assist the AAA Consultants in the formulation of Policies and standards
- Liaise with Law Enforcement Agencies having jurisdiction of the area
- ❖ Act as coordinator between the client and Security Service Provider
- * Administer written examinations and oral interviews to all applicants (Security Officers / Guards)
- Perform such other functions as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Security and Safety Officer / Coordinator			r	First Oceanic Property Management Inc.		-	April 11, 2010 April 30, 201		
•	Area of Responsibility: Offices)	Eastwood	City	Estate	Association,	Libis	(Estate,	Condominiums	and

- Directly reports to the Division Manager
- Conducts the following:
 - Investigation
 - Post-to-post inspection
- Assist the Security and Safety Division in conducting In-house Training / Seminar to all Security Personnel
- Liaise with Law Enforcement Agencies
- ❖ Assist in the conduct of Fire / Earthquake Drills
- Administer written examinations and oral interviews to all applicants (Security Officers / Guards) during the shift
- Perform such other duties as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Deputy for Operation / Admin Head /	Goldleaf Guard Services,	August 2008 to
Head of the Investigation and Inspectorate Group	Inc.	April 10, 2010
Assist the Operation Manager:		

- In the formulation of policies and standards
- In designing budget proposals for any activity
- Conducts the following:
 - Investigation
 - o Inspection and audit
 - Monitoring of all areas
 - o Background checks to all incoming employees
- Member of the Summary Disciplinary Hearing Authority
- Administer written examinations and oral interviews to all applicants (Security Officers / Guards)
- Perform other functions as maybe directed

Detachment Commander	Commander Security	August 01 to
Detachment Commander	Services, Inc.	December 31, 2007
 Account / Project: Department of Education 		
Directly reports to the Head of Security of the	Department of Education	
❖ Conduct daily formation of troops		
❖ Post-to-post inspection		
❖ Assist in making / submitting reports to client		
 Make daily schedule of troops 		
 Make, prepare and submit billings 		
 Perform such other duties as maybe directed by Superior Officers 		

	Shift-In-Charge	Commander Security Services, Inc.	April 16 to July 31, 2007	
--	-----------------	--------------------------------------	------------------------------	--

- Account / Project: De La Salle University-College of Saint Benilde
- Directly reports to the Assistant Detachment Commander
- Assist in the conduct of daily formation of troops
- Post-to-post inspection
- * Assist the Assistant Detachment Commander in making / submitting reports to client
- Make daily schedule of troops
- Perform such other duties as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Mall Security Assistant Supervisor		Tutuban Properties, Inc.	to April 15, 2007
*	Directly reports to the Security Manager		
*	 Conduct investigation during the shift 		
*	Post-to-post inspection		
*	 Assist the Security Manager in the formulation of policies and procedures 		
*	Ensure that the area is complete and manned twenty-four (24) hours		

Act as coordinator between the client and Security Service Provider
 Administer written examinations and oral interviews to all applicants (Security Officers / Guards)

Perform such other duties as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Shift-In-Charge		Sentinel Integrated Services, Inc.	August 31 to November 15, 2005
•	Account / Project: Tutuban Properties, Inc.		
•	Area of Responsibility: Prime Block Building		
	Discorting some state to the Date shows out Commercial or		

- Directly reports to the Detachment Commander
- Conduct daily formation of troops
- Post-to-post inspection
- ❖ Assist the Detachment Commander in making / submitting reports to client
- Make daily schedule of troops
- Perform such other duties as maybe directed by Superior Officers

Government Service:

Clerk II		Department of the Interior and Local Government	August 1999 to May 2000	
Ī	Assignment: Abra Provincial Office, Bangued, Abra			

- * Reports directly to the Admin Manager
- Makes compilation of attendance records of all employees
- Consolidates all reports coming from different Municipal Local Government Operation Officers
- ❖ Make, prepare and submit Minutes of the Meeting every after Meeting
- Perform such other duties as maybe directed by superior officer

Part-time:

College Professor	First Asia Institute of Technology and Humanities	School year 2011 - 2012
College of Public Safety		
 Handled nine (9) subjects per Semester 		

LICENSE/S:

Type	Issued by
Criminologist	Professional Regulation Commission (PRC)
Security Officer	Supervisory Office for Security and Investigation Agencies (SOSIA)
Driver	Land Transportation Office (LTO) with DL Codes A, A1, B, B1, B2, C, D

SECURITY CERTIFICATION/S:

Certification	Issued by		
Certified Security Professional (CSP)	Philippine Society for Industrial Security, Inc. (PSIS)		
Certified Security Management Specialist	Philippine Association of Detective and Protective		
(CSMS)	Agency Operators, Inc. (PADPAO)		
Certified Security Trainer (CST) Philippine Association of Recognized Security Train			
	Schools, Inc. (PARSTS)		
Certified Mall Protection Professional	Mall Security Management Association of the		
(CMPP)	Philippines, Inc. (MSMAP)		

GOVERNMENT EXAMINATIONS TAKEN AND PASSED:

Examination		Rating	D.,	
Inclusive Dates	Туре	Racing	Ву	
November 08, 1998	Career Service Professional	81.89%	Civil Service Commission	
July 26, 1998	PNP Entrance	75.22%	National Police Commission	
March 14 - 16, 1998	Criminologist Licensure	80.15%	Professional Regulation Commission	
March 23, 1997	Police Officer 1 Entrance	84.00%	Civil Service Commission	

TRAINING/S and SEMINAR/S (Internal / External):

Inclusive dates	Title
July 05 - 06, 2017	Occupational First Aid with Basic Life Support
Jan. 31 - Feb. 03, 2017	Professional Mall Security Management Review and Certification Program
August 15 - 16, 2016	Re - Certification Training Course for Investigators
July 06 - 08, 2015	Certification Training Course for Investigators
November 26 - 27, 2013	Compliance Investigation Training / Seminar
June 15 - 16, 2013	Road Traffic Accident Investigation Course

April 24 - 29, 2012	Security Trainers Training Methodology Course (STTMC) Class 07 - 2012	
February 20 - 23, 2012	Certified Security Management Specialist (CSMS) Seminar Class - 30	
April 14 - 17, 2011	Mandatory Training for Fire Safety Practitioners (40 hours) with	
	Certificate of Competency	
March 14 - 18, 2011	Basic Occupational Safety and Health (BOSH) - (40 hours)	
Sept. 28 - Oct. 02, 2009	Certified Security Professional Review Program Class - 157	
September 09 - 18, 2008	Basic Aviation Security Course Class 15 - 2008	
June 23, 2007	Fundamentals of Security	

ORGANIZATIONAL AFFILIATIONS / MEMBERSHIP:

Philippine Society for Industrial Security, Inc. (PSIS)
 Long Maroon Line, Inc. (LML)
 Member

SKILL/S:

- Computer literate (MS Word, Excel, Powerpoint)
- Driving (Manual and Automatic)
- Knowledge in Basic Self-defense

CHARACTER REFERENCE/S:

MR. DANTE L. DAOANG JR., CSP
 MR. ROY ALLAN O. GUYJUCO
 MR. GIAN KARLO G. AQUINO, CSP
 Security and Safety Practitioner
 Security and Safety Practitioner

I do hereby certify that the above statements are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and ability.

Applicant's signature